Guide to the Doris Ulmann Photograph Collection ca. 1910-1934 PR 72
New-York Historical Society
- middle aged, seated on wicker chair: longish straight dark hair and mustache, suit, vest, tie, high shirt collar, 1916 (Item 2716)
- young, musician, standing holding and strumming a very large guitar-like instrument, smiling, longish, thin straight hair, high collar, unusual bow tie, jacket (Item 2717)
- unusual outdoor scene, two men, and artist and buyer in conversation in front of rows of canvases propped up against a building on a sidewalk; artist with beret, jacket, white shirt; "buyer" with dark hair, eyeglasses, suit, tie (Item 2718)
- see 2718, possibly same place; artist seated at easel in what looks like daylight, sketching with vine of charcoal, looking right at camera, as if doing portrait; middle aged, bald, mustache, cleft chin, work shirt (Item 2719)
- young, jacket, vest, tie, short, thick, straight salt and pepper hair, seated, looking intently into camera, a framed pencil or charcoal portrait of a young girl is partially visible in upper left corner hanging on wall [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century] (Item 2720)
- couple both seated on porch; she: thin, gaunt-looking, thin gray hair parted in middle pulled back, dark cardigan, dark gray dress, holding cane or walking stick; he: wide brimmed straw hat, white sideburns, beard, work shirt, suspenders, holding cane (Item 2721)
- group of 4 country men and Niles seated outside under a tree; Niles is writing in a note book, all are in shirtsleeves, some in overalls, two have hats [Niles, John Jacob, (1892-1980) folklorist, musician, Ulmann's assistant] (Item 2722)
- top hat, white tie, top coat, etc., holding overcoat, standing, walking stick [Niles, John Jacob, (1892-1980) folklorist, musician, Ulmann's assistant] (Item 2723)
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie, seated at desk, writing [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2724)
  #1229-1231, 2143-2152, 2724, 2984 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. ." but not this image, mat is crumbling
- middle aged, balding, medium light short hair on sides and back, in profile, seated with hands on back chair, suit, tie (Item 2725)
  other images of this subject in collection
- young, wiry, salt and pepper, curly disheveled hair, black bow-tie type tie, jacket, vest, seated on sofa, book base in background (Item 2726)
  #2726, 2727 same subject, same sitting; other images of this subject in collection
- young, wiry, salt and pepper, curly disheveled hair, black bow-tie type tie, jacket, vest, seated on sofa, book base in background, 1919 (Item 2727)
- older, white straight hair, parted on side, mustache, seated with tree leaves in foreground, open book in lap, suit, vest, tie, high collar, a medal pinned to lapel (Item 2728)
- older middle aged, thing, white straight hair parted in middle, round eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie, stout, seated, arms crossed, in front of window, 1917 (Item 2729)
- young, very thick salt and pepper, but mostly dark, straight hair, mustache, round dark-rimmed eyeglasses, suit, vest tie, seated writing on pad propped on his knee (Item 2730)
- young, dark thick wavy hair, striped double breasted suit, tie, seated on desk or bench, handsome (Item 2731)
  there are other images of this subject in collection
- older, very white longish hair, balding on top, white sideburns, mustache, beard, suit, seated at desk, open book, writing on paper, cluttered bookcase in background (Item 2732)
  #2732, 2738 same subject
- older middle aged, thin light gray hair, suit, vest, tie (Item 2733)
- middle aged, short bushy hair, medium light, bushy eyebrows, checked suit, vest, tie, chrysanthemum in lapel, black armband, seated, open book in lap, book case in background [Thayer, William Sydney, M.D., LL.D., Hon. F.R.C.P.I., Professor of Medicine] (Item 2734)
- young, thin dark straight hair combed back, mustache, beard, round eyeglasses, striped shirt, tie, jacket (Item 2735)
- middle aged, smooth, medium dark hair, suit, vest, tie, seated (Item 2736)
- young, thick dark hair, round eyeglasses, suit, vest tie, holding book in hands, seated (Item 2737)
  others of this subject in collection
- older, very white longish hair, balding on top, eyeglasses, white sideburns, mustache, beard, suit, seated at desk (Item 2738)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, animated, actor? (Item 2739)
  #2739-2745 same subject
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, tie, cigar in ashtray in foreground, animated, actor? (Item 2740)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, looking forlorn, actor? (Item 2741)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, leaning back in chair, actor? (Item 2742)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, leaning sideways in chair, actor? (Item 2743)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, leaning sideways in chair, looking up over left shoulder, actor? (Item 2744)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, actor? (Item 2745)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2746)
  #1990, 2135-2142, 2746-2751, 2937, 2983 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2747)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2748)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2749)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2750)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2751)
- bald, white/white mustache, thick rimmed and thick lenses round eyeglasses, seated, suit, vest, tie [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2752)
  #2110-2113, 2713, 2752, 2929 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image; this image is a photogravure and appears to be a page from the book, identified on back
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie, seated at desk writing [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook] (Item 2753)
  #2753-2757, 2979 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie, seated at desk writing [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook] (Item 2754)
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie, seated open book in lap, pen or pencil in right hand [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook] (Item 2755)
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie, seated open book in lap, pen or pencil in right hand [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook] (Item 2756)
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook] (Item 2757)
- white hair, balding, gray suit, holding paper [Galsworthy, John (1867-1933) English writer] (Item 2758)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2759)
  #2175-2190, 2759, 2995 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery of American Editors", but not this image
- gray suit, vest, tie, smooth medium light hair, seated with book or notes on desk or table, cigar (?) in left hand, oval eyeglasses [Cosgrave, John O'Hara, Editor, the Sunday World] (Item 2760)
- straight dark hair, parted on side, pince nez eyeglasses, high collar, tie, white lab coat, seated at desk, hand on open book or notebook, desk lamp [Palmer, Walter W., Associate Professor of Medicine, Columbia], 1918 (Item 2761)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding eyeglasses [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur] (Item 2762)
  #2762-2768, 3012 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery of.. .", but not this image
- thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur] (Item 2763)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding book [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur] (Item 2764)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding book [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur] (Item 2765)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding book [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur] (Item 2766)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding and reading open book [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur] (Item 2767)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding book [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur] (Item 2768)
- older, seated outside, vines on wall in background, felt hat, rumpled jacket, vest, tie, white shirt, white beard and mustache (Item 2769)
  #2769-2771 same subject
- older, seated outside, felt hat, rumpled jacket, vest, tie, white shirt, dirty and torn apron, shoe form (?) in hand, a cobbler?, white beard and mustache (Item 2770)
- older, seated outside, trees in background, felt hat, rumpled jacket, vest, tie, white shirt, white beard and mustache (Item 2771)
- young to middle aged, hat covered in bright sunlight, mustache, work shirt, overalls, seated, with a metal scoop, scooping grain from a large wooden grain measure (Item 2772)
  on back of mount, in DU's handwriting: Doris Ulmann, 1000 Park Avenue, New York City, II The Miller; in other hand, blue pencil: U.1/6; on front of mat, lower left, pencil, not DU's hand: The Miller
- middle aged, tousled short dark hair, work shirt, overalls, standing in work yard, holding wheelbarrow with large wooden wheels (Item 2773)
  #2773, 2865 same subject
- turned away from camera, standing holding lines from wagon on dock or deck of boat, striped shirt, cap (Item 2774)
  possibly a pigment or oil transfer print, not platinum
- young middle aged, cap, striped work shirt, rolled up sleeves, standing at table or bench, appears to be kneading bread (Item 2775)
- standing inside a granary full of grain, with shovel, wheel barrow in foreground, hat, work shirt, suspenders (Item 2776)
- middle aged, hat, mustache, lanky, standing, white sweater-type shirt, boots, in a lumber yard, standing on pile of rough cut wood, holding a log with bark on it (Item 2777)
- young, cap, mustache, striped work shirt, sleeves rolled up, undershirt, seated with elbows on knees, holding a pipe (Item 2778)
  #2778, 2779 same subject
- young, cap, mustache, striped work shirt, sleeves rolled up, undershirt, seated with elbows on knees, holding a pipe (Item 2779)
- older middle aged, thing white hair, eyeglasses, stubble beard and mustache, striped work shirt, suspenders, holding asparagus in hand, basket between legs (Item 2780)
- older, white hair, long sideburns, beard, mustache, tawny complexion, seated, light colored shirt, suspenders (Item 2781)
  many other images of this subject in collection
- older, dark felt hat, white sideburns (Mennonite style), long beard, jacket, white shirt, seated with open bible (?) in lap (Item 2782)
- middle aged, dark complexion, white frizzy short hair, white mustache, beard, standing in front of trellis, sweat-soaked work shirt, watch chain (Item 2783)
- middle aged, large-brimmed straw hat, trim mustache and beard (salt and pepper), smiling, dark shirt, suspenders, seated, holding a pipe (Item 2784)
- older, thing, felt hat, white mustache, sharp features, seated outside, striped suit jacket, bow tie (Item 2785)
  many others of this subject in collection, part of mat is cut off
- older man in foreground, seated, white work shirt, striped apron or overalls, felt hat, seated in straw in front of a small building; boy (maybe 14-15) behind, same striped apron or overalls, work shirt, dark thick hair, holding a rake or broom handle (Item 2786)
  mat and mount torn and worn
- older, dark felt hat, suit jacket, white shirt, white sideburns and beard (Mennonite style), seated (Item 2787)
- both men middle aged, mustaches, caps; one in light colored work shirt, other dark shirt; both seated in work yard or dock area, 1917 (Item 2788)
  doesn't look like a platinum print, is a little shiny, perhaps an oil transfer print
- older, distinguished-looking, white hair and mustache, suit jacket, vest, pants, watch chain, no tie, seated on porch, holding a pipe (Item 2789)
- older, dark felt hat, white sideburns (Mennonite style), long beard, jacket, white shirt, seated with bible (?) in lap (Item 2790)
- older, felt hat, seated outside on bench, clapboard wall behind, somewhat rumpled topcoat, vest, pants, white shirt, watch chain, holding pipe (Item 2791)
- middle aged to older, wide brimmed straw hat, heavy salt and pepper beard and mustache, plaid clean work shirt, suspenders, seated holding a folded newspaper, smiling (Item 2792)
- middle aged to older, short wavy white or blonde hair, stubbly beard and mustache, pointed nose, clean light colored work shirt, suspenders, seated in rocking chair (Item 2793)
- older or not so old but looks like he doesn't have his teeth, thick dark hair, dark round eyeglasses, work shirt, overalls, holding a chair leg or back, a clamp on a bench at side, a carpenter? (Item 2794)
- older, white mustache, felt hat, pipe (corn cob?), tweed jacket, vest, ribbon bow tie (Item 2795)
- older, white mustache, felt hat, striped jacket, vest, bow tie, smiling (Item 2796)
- older, long distinctive nose, nice straw hat, dark suit, vest, tie, seated with closed book (bible?) (Item 2797)
  there are other images of this subject
- middle aged to older, white short hair, mustache, dark work shirt, vest, almost smiling, looking energetic and engaging (Item 2798)
- middle aged, thin straight hair, longish, part on side, long mustache, suit, high collar, tie, standing with elbow on bookshelf (?), holding open book, 1917 (Item 2799)
  #2799, 2803 same subject
- white suit, seated in wicker chair, probably outside, reading a book, lit cigarette in right hand [Jaeger, Charles H., Ulmann's husband, Physician, and Assistant Professor of Orthopaedics, Columbia], 1916 (Item 2800)
- round eyeglasses, horse shoe tie pin, middle aged, stout [Tilney, Frederic, Professor of Neurology and Neuro-Anatomy, Columbia], 1918 (Item 2801)
  #1092, 1255, 1448, 1894, 2290 same subject, subject is in "XXIV Portraits.. .", but not this image
- young, rough complexion, dark thick straight hair, parted on side, bushy eyebrows, suit, vest, tie, 1917 (Item 2802)
- middle aged, thin straight hair, longish, part on side, long mustache, suit, high collar, tie, seated, right hand on desk, 1917 (Item 2803)
- pince nez eyeglasses, bow tie, middle aged, seated [Long, Ray, editor, The Cosmopolitan] (Item 2804)
  #1275, 2804 same subject; this is a photogravure print and appears to be a page cut from the book; on back of print in unknown handwriting, in pencil is subject's name, title of book, etc.
- middle aged, light colored short hair, parted on side, striped suit jacket, tie, smiling [Lorimer, George Horace, editor in chief, Saturday Evening Post] (Item 2805)
  #1185, 2805, 2936 same subject; this is a photogravure print and appears to be a page cut from the book; on back of print in unknown handwriting, in pencil is subject's name, title of book, etc.
- young middle aged, lanky, spiky short medium light hair, mustache, long nose, seated, dark work shirt, apron, holding a pipe (Item 2806)
- older, wide brimmed straw hat, round eyeglasses, mustache, undershirt (Item 2807)
- older, white/gray hair, longish beard, mustache, 1919 (Item 2808)
  #2013, 2014, 2023, 2024, 2043-2046, 2171, 2172, 2808-2810, 2818, 2822, 2832-2835 same subject
- older, white/gray hair, longish beard, mustache, cap, leather jacket, military uniform, crocheted scarf, unlit cigarette in mouth, 1919 (Item 2809)
- older, white/gray hair, longish beard, mustache, cap, dress military uniform, medals, 1919 (Item 2810)
- older, straight white hair, parted on side, mustache, beard, suit, vest, tie (Item 2811)
- older, long white beard, balding, mustache, seated with overcoat, hat, umbrella, 1917 (Item 2812)
  #2812-2814 same subject
- older, long white beard, balding, mustache, seated with overcoat, hat, umbrella, 1917 (Item 2813)
- older, long white beard, balding, mustache, standing with overcoat, hat, umbrella, 1917 (Item 2814)
  image is unusual vertical proportion, possible cropped, pencil lines are drawn on tissue, possibly to note where a new mat might be cut to frame the image
- young, wide brimmed felt hat (like a "Mountie" hat), plaid kerchief around neck, jacket and vest, looks like studio setting, 1917 (Item 2815)
- young, wide brimmed felt hat (like a "Mountie" hat), plaid kerchief around neck, jacket and vest, looks like studio setting, 1917 (Item 2816)
- middle aged, dark short hair, mustache, white tie, high collar, top coat, kilt, shawl standing in front of decorative paneled door, 1917 (Item 2817)
- white/gray long beard, cap with ear flaps, canvas jacket, leather shirt or bib, holding pipe, 1919 (Item 2818)
- older, dark felt hat, long white beard and sideburns Mennonite style, dark jacket, white shirt, hands on book or books (?) (Item 2819)
- middle aged to older, felt hat with brim turned up, very short beard, round eyeglasses, gaunt, work shirt, overalls, leaning on railing in front of barn-type building (Item 2820)
- middle aged, thick medium light straight hair, parted on side, mustache, white shirt, undershirt, suspenders, seated (Item 2821)
- middle aged, thin short straight hair, beard, light colored or gray, canvas jacket, leather vest (Item 2822)
- older, lots of light or white, long hair, tousled, beard, mustache, polka dot shirt; standing in gate of unpainted picket fence; safety pin in pants' waistband; looks like close relative of subject in 2503 (same nose and shape of face) (Item 2823)
- young man, two boys, (father and sons?), all seated or kneeling by a water pump, two stacked buckets of berries (?), all in overalls and work shirts, boys in caps, man in felt hat (Item 2824)
- older, white hair and mustache, smartly dressed, suit jacket, vest, ribbon bow tie, seated on porch step with cane (?) or umbrella, minister (?) (Item 2825)
- two men, seated, in work clothes, suspenders; one in light colored shirt and hat, hands in lap; other in darker shirt and hat, arms crossed across chest (Item 2826)
  print is not platinum, possibly oil or pigment transfer
- two men at vegetable market; one is standing, light colored shirt and apron, holding a bunch of celery; other is seated with a head of cauliflower in his hands (Item 2827)
- missing from box (Item 2828)
  photo and mat missing from box/no Xerox in binder
- older, lots of light or white, long hair, tousled, beard, mustache, polka dot shirt; standing in front of unpainted picket fence; looks like close relative of subject in 2503 (same nose and shape of face) (Item 2829)
- young to middle aged man at docks with nets (Item 2830)
- older man in foreground with plump cheeks, big nose, white hat with dark band, lots of curly white hair, beard, mustache, sideburns, suit, vest, no tie, seated with newspaper; 2nd older man in background standing, soft focus (Item 2831)
- middle aged, thin short straight hair, beard, light colored or gray, canvas jacket, leather vest, 1919 (Item 2832)
- older, white/gray hair, longish beard, mustache, in tuxedo, medals or decorations on jacket, holding book or paper, cane, 1919 (Item 2833)
- older, white/gray hair, longish beard, mustache, in tuxedo, medals or decorations on jacket, holding a cigarette, 1919 (Item 2834)
- older, white/gray hair, longish beard, mustache, canvas jacket, dark cap, leather vest, holding pipe and pouch of tobacco, 1919 (Item 2835)
- two men, both in dark collarless jackets, short, Mennonite-style beards and sideburns; man on left is younger, dark hair parted in middle, holds a book in lap (bible?); man on right is older, white hair (Item 2836)
- middle aged, thick medium light straight hair, parted on side, mustache, white shirt, undershirt, suspenders, seated (Item 2837)
- middle aged, cap, longish mustache, work shirt, sleeves rolled up, working on a barrel (?) with hammer with long claw tooth, in a wood (?) shop (Item 2838)
  #2838, 2839 same subject
- middle aged, cap, longish mustache, work shirt, suspenders, sleeves rolled up, seated eating lunch bread, other things wrapped in wax paper (?), open thermos bottle, lunch spread out on barrel in #2838 (Item 2839)
- young middle aged, tattered straw hat, seated in front of stone building wall, work shirt, overalls, holding a broom handle (Item 2840)
  there are others of this subject
- older, longish white beard, large felt hat, dark suit, ribbon tie, dapper-looking, seated outside, stone wall in background (Item 2841)
- middle aged to older, white short hair, mustache, dark work shirt, vest, almost smiling, looking energetic and engaging, standing in doorway to barn or garage (Item 2842)
- older, balding, white straight hair, sideburns, beard, mouth agape, clean work shirt, holding felt hat, standing on porch or just near a building (Item 2843)
- middle aged, older, gaunt, large-brimmed straw hat, longish mustache, clean work shirt, suspenders, standing leaning on railing or some other wood structure, hands clasped (Item 2844)
- older, longish white beard, large felt hat, dark suit, ribbon tie, dapper-looking, seated outside, holding newspaper in lap (Item 2845)
- older, longish white beard, large felt hat, dark suit, ribbon tie, dapper-looking, seated outside, holding newspaper in lap, almost smiling (Item 2846)
- older, long white beard, sideburns, mustache, felt hat, clean work shirt, seated leaning against building, hands clasped around knee (Item 2847)
  #2847, 2848 same subject
- older, long white beard, sideburns, mustache, felt hat, clean work shirt, seated, leaning over, hands clasped (Item 2848)
- young, felt hat, dark hair, round eyeglasses, work shirt, vest, striped pants, standing with pencil (?) in right hand writing in a book or journal, sort of smiling (Item 2849)
- older, gaunt, white mustache, new-looking straw hat with striped band, clean suit, vest, tie, white shirt, seated holding a cane (Item 2850)
- middle aged, balding, visor, diamond-patterned shirt, tie, suspenders, standing emptying a wooden box of some kind of material or possibly type into a barrel or bin (Item 2851)
- young middle aged man, standing on porch, felt hat, overalls, bucket resting on railing at his side; boy, possibly black, seated on porch, felt hat, white shirt, overalls (Item 2852)
- young middle aged, floppy straw or cotton hat with dark band, smiling, holding pipe in mouth, work shirt, suspenders, belt, standing against wood siding (Item 2853)
- man in foreground middle aged, short thick medium dark hair, mustache, seated holding what look like blacksmith tools (hammer and tong); second man is standing, younger, long medium dark hair; both clean work shirt, overalls; father/son? (Item 2854)
  #2641, 2854 same subjects